Yeah, we're going to talk about starting
over financially, data centers, AI,
jobs, and a whole lot in this video. But
it is the evening of Lauren's birthday,
and I'm going to go to bed after I post
this video. We're going to set the
expiration for that birthday coupon
code, Lauren's birthday code, uh, to
just a limited quantity of coupons left.
So that way it'll expire while I'm
asleep. [laughter] So, make sure you
take advantage of that over at meet.com.
In this video, we're going to go through
14 different questions that you all have
submitted totally for free in the Meet
Kevin app that you as a watcher can do
this as well. And we're going to
literally cover topics including what do
we think about backyards with homes.
We'll talk about, hey, if you're
starting over financially, what would
you do? We'll talk about the jobs
report. We'll talk about private equity
exposure forum from from your job and
how to diversify from there. We'll also
talk about data center stocks and
infrastructure,
PEG ratios, how they work a little bit
on real estate. We got a lot to cover
here, so let's get started. We'll spend
maybe 2 minutes on average, I'd say, per
question, so I don't want to get carried
away and go too ridiculously deep. But
let's start with this scenario here.
Imagine you're 33 years old on the verge
of getting married, effectively starting
over financially. You have a current net
worth. I've added this up. It works out
to about $299,000. Call it $300,000. Uh
given the baseline assets and this major
upcoming life transition, what
step-by-step strategy would you execute?
All right. To try to rebuild or build a
$1 million net worth within 5 years and
then tax efficiency and some other
things. Okay. So first things first, I
generally don't think of marriage as a
huge transition. Now everybody can be
different on this, but typically I think
before you get married and religions
will differ on this, right? But you
should already be together with a person
for a while. Best case scenario, you're
already living with them for a while.
You kind of already know is this going
to work longer term? And that way you're
going in 300K. Not sure if you're going
to do a prenup or not. Topic for a
different video there. But definitely
look into that. If you're going to do
one, talk to an attorney. Very
important. Uh but it shouldn't be that
much of a transition. Getting into
marriage should be smooth because you
should really be going from the
relationship that you're in to just
continuously being in that relationship.
Instead, what's really important is if
you're talking about starting over
financially there, and you didn't
mention any kind of job here, the most
important thing, especially if you're
getting married, is making sure you've
got a job. Doesn't have to be the
greatest beall endall job. You just got
to start somewhere. I know somebody
who's lost their job and they were
making pretty decent money and now they
drop down to work minimum wage so that
at the same time they can go back to
school. I'm not saying do that, but you
got to stay busy doing something that
you could grow in. So, personally, I'd
go dig trenches for an electrician if I
had no skills and I'd start learning the
electrical industry and after four
years, I'd get my own electrical
contractor's license or plumbing or
HVAC, whatever. trades are great right
now. I also think there's a really good
strategic opportunity to get into real
estate and start building a business now
because if you can build a business
between 2026 and say 2030 as a real
estate agent or real estate lender when
most people are leaving the industry
because rates are high, you're already
going to have a reputation. You're
already going to be in it for four or
five years when rates come down again
because eventually they will. and boom,
now you've set yourself up for success.
I'd start having those thoughts now and
see, you could actually combine that.
But it's all, you know, you could have
one of those minimum wage jobs and get
your real estate license. You could do
these things together. Just ideas. But
it all comes down to income. You've got
to crank income over the next 5 years.
just because you got, you know, $300,000
in these accounts. Look, it doesn't
really matter what you invested into
because if you have any form of
diversification,
it's going to be tough to get to a mill
within 5 years unless you hit a strong
yolo. I think the better option is
maximize maximize maximize your income
and write off as much as you can as an
independent contractor. Even if you are
employed somewhere, have that side
hustle. Make sure you're writing off
absolutely everything you can. If you
got a job or you work for yourself, you
should look into the SE IRA or max out
your 401k at your job. And of course, if
you're under that income limit,
contribute to your Roth as well. Big fan
of those. But other than that, I those
are little rounding errors in uh
building a retirement portfolio. Focus
on your income first. So, I'm less
worried about the marriage being a big
transition. And I'm more worried about
what are you doing income-wise? We got
to focus on getting that income up so
that hopefully in 5 years we can
actually be cranking dough and that's
what builds us a business or a salary
that we can really build that
million-doll net worth with. Okay, let's
go on to the next question. Next
question here is -23,000 jobs in this
last report and that number is likely to
be revised down next month because
historically they do trend down in
revisions. Yes, because the numbers are
always revised down. Yeah, I mean there
there there have been times they get
revised up, but you're right, it does
seem to trend down uh especially in this
environment. Fewer work uh force
participants, fewer jobs being
supposedly lost to AI efficiency games
against employment is a lagging
indicator. learned that from you early
on. Therefore, when does this begin to
manifest itself in the markets? Bad jobs
reports no longer seem to affect the
markets. The Fed is printing for the
BOJ, but that doesn't seem to affect the
market. Rising oil doesn't move the
market. Right? So, here's the thing. In
my opinion, what's happening in our
economy is the economy is so hyped up on
artificial intelligence that we are
plowing through a world of sin. We're
plowing through an economy that's
bleeding out. We're literally like an
artery is just spewing blood out the
bottom. Maybe not spewing, but we're
we're dripping out. We're bleeding out
slowly. It's going to take some time,
but we're bleeding out slowly. Uh and
you know, we keep getting cuts, tariffs,
oil, war, private credit. You know,
another private credit firm went a belly
up today. Uh and what you end up finding
is that all of these are getting papered
over by the wealth and the spending that
is coming from the stock market going
up. More the stock market goes up, the
more of a wealth effect. The more people
are spending on travel, food,
entertainment, retail spending is
through the roof. Personal savings are
in the toilet.
So, we're kind of living our best lives
because the party is going or at least
some people are. Not everybody is,
obviously.
This is not sustainable.
At some point, something will give. And
this is why I've been overly cautious
the last few years because we don't know
how long it's going to last, how long
the music's going to keep playing. But
at some point whether you know it it it
could be something as simple as
Enthropic and OpenAI IPO their stocks
tank you know SpaceX fell 50% in the
first uh you know month but these guys
let's say tank even more because they're
only AI and they don't have all the
other like Starlinker rockets and stuff
like that. So what ends up happening
those guys can't raise capital anymore.
the last sort of spending gets sent into
artificial intelligence, uh, you know,
data center spend, and the cycle
screeches to a halt. When that AI cycle
screeches to a halt, there's we're going
to be in for a world of hurt. So, to
answer your question, it's it's not
actually
the labor market that really pushes us
into a recession. It's the spending
stopping. At some point, the spending
will stop. Not yet. We're not We're not
there yet. At some point, the credit
cycle will end and the spending will be
forced to stop because nobody's going to
finance it anymore. Uh then we'll see
layoffs rise into a labor market that is
way too weak to absorb those. And that's
why employment will be a lagging
indicator. Oil going up is just sort of
another one of those little cuts just
like tariffs. These are all little cuts.
But so far we've been able to paper over
everything because artificial
intelligence has been frankly a gift to
this economy. You know, I don't think
our economy would have been as strong in
2023, four, five, or six, last four
years if it weren't for artificial
intelligence. Uh and and I'm not saying
that's a good thing. Uh I mean, I do
think there there are good things that
come out of artificial intelligence. Uh
but I I I do think it is healthy for an
economy to reset and uh that time will
come and I'm very concerned that Kevin
Worsh isn't going to be there to bail
people out. The only thing he'll do is
drop rates to zero which is why earlier
I mentioned get your real estate license
and lending license. Get ready, right?
It's going to be a crazy time. Um but uh
but there'll be a lot of opportunity and
a lot of money to be made. So, so the
way I look at it is anything you invest
today, and this is why the same thing
with the person who's like starting over
financially, anything you invest today,
uh, not none of this in the video,
personalized financial advice,
obviously. I don't know what your full
situation, but um, anything you invest
in the stock market today, you've just
got to be comfortable with if it goes
down 80%. Are you going bankrupt and
starting over? And if the answer is no,
I don't care. Just going to keep making
money or, you know, whatever, great,
perfect. Then you might be ready. I
don't know that you'll actually be
ready. I don't know that anybody's
actually ready for a crisis when one
comes. But, uh, good question. But, but
really, that is why the labor market
lags because it is not the catalyst that
breaks, uh, the camel's back. something
else breaks the camel's back and then
layoffs happen and then the employment
data really gets ugly.
All right. Now, uh but it is evidence of
a slow bleed for sure. Here we got um a
question from Joe. Longtime fan. Uh
let's see here. [laughter]
Okay, I get the joke about the pitches.
That's great. Joe's basically saying if
you use the coupon code, you don't hear
the pitches anymore. [laughter]
Uh here's my conundrum. Rough net worth
breakdown. 35% equity in a private uh
equitybacked company I work for. Okay.
Basically, this could be uh you know a
local software startup that has a bunch
of uh private equity investments.
Private equity is going to try to IPO
this one day or roll it up. Uh and you
own equity in it, but you have no idea
when that's going to happen. No idea.
That's typically how it is. You have 46%
of your net worth in public markets, 12%
in cash, and 7% in home equity. Okay,
great. So, uh, so roughly 80% equity,
and half of it is illquid.
While you're working at your PE firm,
uh, or it's not a PE firm, but the firm
that's PE back, I personally would just
pretend that I didn't have any equity
stake in the company that I work for.
Because the worst case scenario is your
company, I don't think this will happen.
I don't know what your company is, but I
don't think this will happen. Just
saying the worst case scenario, your
company goes bankrupt. All your shares
go to zero. Now you have no job, and
that part of your net worth is gone. So,
I like being mega conservative with this
and and so I just pretend and go, "Okay,
I if those shares do something, it's
icing on the cake, but I'm going to live
based on what I'm making. I'm going to
do my best at my company to help make
those shares go up in value, but I'm not
going to track them. I'm not going to
pay attention to it. I'm just going to
know they exist and forget about it as
much as you can." Obviously, you're
going to know. So, uh, then I would be
very conservative, uh, with growing the
rest of my portfolio. If you've got 7%
in home equity, you relatively thin in
home equity. Uh, I mean, I don't know
what these numbers are. It depends on
how large these numbers are, right?
Maybe these are all millions of dollars
and 7% is is already a few hundred,000.
But, uh, but assuming that's not the
case, since you're asking for some
insights here, maybe it is. uh you know,
I think there's an opportunity to uh
build up uh your cash, use that and only
consider paying down your mortgage if
your rate is greater than 5 and a half%.
Maybe 5%. So, if you got a rate of like
6 or 7%, I'd start paying that puppy
off. That is the easiest ROI. And now
you can actually take some of your cash
or your extra savings every month, start
paying down that equity, uh, well,
paying down your debt and building your
equity, uh, and you actually make
yourself more resilient in the event
there's, you know, an oopsy doopsies in
the future. I know that's maybe not
deemed to be the, you know, highest
leverage move, but I think that's a
great way to diversify your portfolio a
little bit since you've already got 46,
you know, percent in in uh in public
markets and uh the rest compared to your
real estate net worth and cash is is
relatively on the small side. Uh so
obviously whatever you can do to
increase your income at your job or a
side hustle is a bonus. Not everybody
can pull off a side hustle. Some jobs
keep you really busy and that's okay
because you should have most of your
upside at your primary gig anyway. The
side hustle is a great tool for having
some extra write offs and maybe one day
that side hustle can develop into
something larger. But uh I think you're
in a good spot to think about that debt.
Now if you've got a super low loan uh
interest rate or let's say so maybe
you're at 2.9 3%. So obviously a lot
more painful to pay that off. Something
that you could consider for being more
aggressive, and this is if you really
want to be aggressive, and that depends
on your income. So, you look into
getting a home equity line of credit or
just refinance the puppy. You got 7%
home equity. That's not going to work.
Never mind. I was thinking it'd be nice
to be able to get you in a rental, but
with 7% home equity, it's it's like you
just bought the place with 5% down, you
know? Um, so that's not going to happen.
Um, and if you moved and rented it out,
you'd probably have a negative cash flow
at 7% equity. You got to build up the
equity no matter what. You got you just
got to build up the equity. I think
that's the best answer. Build up the
equity in the home. Try to increase your
income. And uh you know, if you've got
any kind of other debt against those
stocks you didn't mention, you do uh
you'd want to pay that off right away.
But uh given that you didn't mention it,
I I don't think you do. So that sounds
good. I like the company I work for.
Happy to own the shares I do. I've
already taken some off the table once.
Another PE recap should free up some
more later. Uh I'm not uh asking how to
get out. I'm asking how to size
everything more. Right. Does the frozen
35% count against my entire budget?
Again, I personally think you set that
almost to zero. So, instead, let's say
you had $46 in public equity, 12% in C
or $12 in cash, and $7 in home equity.
You got $65 in total in this example,
right? Uh that means to me, you are 70%
stocks and 7 divided by 65 only 10% home
equity. And I'd like to try to get that
to be a little bit more even. even
uh Okay. Um yeah, so I think that's uh
that's that's that's the way I would
look at it, right? Okay, cool. Here's
the next one. Kevin, you said data
centers and hyperscalers will suffer in
the long term and prefer not to hold
those stocks.
That's pretty aggressive. [laughter]
That's probably true. Uh CMIw
uh hold on a sec. I don't know what that
means. Correct me if I'm wrong.
[laughter]
I've never heard of that before. I've
never seen that in my life. I must be
sheltered. Uh correct me if I'm wrong.
Your reason is that uh they will be
holding outdated chips which they have
paid a premium for. Yeah. So I mean
that's that's one of the reasons.
However, even when tokens become
cheaper, demand for AI will remain
strong. Right. This is the whole Jeans
thing, Javon's paradox that you hear
Satya Nadella talk about and you see it
on Ax blah blah blah. Uh, in fact, I
could argue that it'll increase since
people will start to experiment more and
do more. Hence, won't data centers still
be a good business even though chips are
outdated? They have a high likelihood of
being utilized. Notably, won't Oracle do
well, especially with their bring your
own chip model. It further reduces their
risk. Okay, a lot to unpackage here. So,
let's let's start from the top. I don't
like commodities. I like things that are
uh representative of pricing power. So,
I'm a big fan of Nvidia and Nvidia's
chips. Uh, maybe not for the next decade
because they have such a high bar for
growth that I don't know if that's going
to stay elevated at these growth levels,
which really affects their valuation.
More on that. We'll do Nvidia in just a
moment when we do the KPEG versus PEG
ratio. I'll break that down. But, uh, so
I like pricing power companies. I
personally just don't think data center
chips have pricing power. I think they
might now because there's a shortage,
but when there's a shortage, you don't
have pricing power because you're
better. You have pricing power because
there's a shortage.
That's very different. It's sort of
like, you know, if you're in the middle
of a desert and you're super thirsty and
somebody's got, you know, a little sack
of water, you don't care where that
water is from. You'll just drink. You'll
pay a hundred bucks for that sack of
water and you'll drink it. You don't
even really care what's potentially in
it because the near-term risk of death,
[laughter] right, is so high that the
pricing power is so high because there's
a shortage of water. Say, you know,
assuming you're dehydrated in the
desert, right? Uh, you know, whereas
when you go to the store today and
there's no shortage of water, it's like,
all right, well, there's a water
fountain that's free next to the
bathrooms. It's kind of gross sometimes,
you know, the back of grocery store
water fountains, but they work. That's
free. You could go get a refrigerated
Danny for like a buck 50 up at the
front, or you can get the Evian for $3,
right? Uh and and so the people grabbing
the Evian are proving that pricing power
for H2O, the same freaking molecule,
exists. Uh I like Evian, too. I don't
know how they make it taste different,
but whatever.
So, the point is that whole example is
to say that when something is a
commodity like compute, the reality is
in the long term, I don't care if I get
it from SpaceX,
Riot, which was a crypto company, right?
They just did a $9 billion deal with
Anthropic because Anthropic doesn't care
if it's Riot's chips, Oracle's chips,
you know, uh, SpaceX's chips,
coreweaves, and everything. They don't
care. They just want the compute. And
so, they're not actually choosing SpaceX
because SpaceX is a better company.
They're choosing them because they have
the product. In the future, I expect
there won't be a shortage. There won't
be you won't be parched in a desert.
Instead, you will be in a grocery store
full of water bottles.
And then the challenge is going to be,
okay, well, what's the difference?
Because this isn't even comparing Evian
to Dani. This is literally comparing a
GB300 at Nebius to a GB300 at Microsoft
to a GB300 at SpaceX. Why would I pay
$11 at one when I could pay six at
another, assuming they have the same
availability? I wouldn't. I'm going to
pay all the costs are going to converge
to the same price. So there's literally
no difference
again assuming the same availability for
the same hardware. There's no difference
between pricing power for these
companies. So these companies can't
really prove pricing power. And I think
that's why when you notice SpaceX raised
money for data centers before it was
SpaceX, when it was just XAI, they were
paying 12 a.5% on their debt. So risky.
It's going to commoditize. Coreweave
spends over 10% on interest. It's risky.
It's going to commoditize. Everybody in
their mom knows it's going to
commoditize.
And so this is where if you watch my
bifurcation video that I posted this
morning, we know there are two elements
to uh this this LLM compute. There's the
LLM compute side you're talking about
which is the enterprise compute
the Alibaba models the meta openweight
models the deepseek models the Kimmy
openweight models doesn't matter all
those models we can use at an enterprise
like house hacker reinvest we could use
those and we can actually solve problems
whether it's in stock AI or homes AI or
the other things that we're building we
can functionally put these things to
work but we don't need GB300 00s. We
don't need bleeding edge. We need the
5090. We don't even need the RTX 6000
because it has way too much VRAM. 96 GB
of VRAM. We don't need that much. We
need like 32 because we just need many
of them.
So, point is
enterprise AI won't give a flying f
about what these data centers are
putting in.
the enterprise AI that can be done on a
smaller scale with workstations. There's
money to be made there. I'm a big fan of
that and I'm a big fan of the companies
that can actually turn AI into money.
Palunteer is a great example. Axon is
going to be another example in my
opinion. No guarantees. Uh that you know
Salesforce, we'll see. Can they turn it
around? Can they actually integrate AI
into Salesforce and make it something
that it wasn't before? We will see. Same
thing for UiPath. We will see. So those
companies will be able to prove their
pricing power. Palanteer is already
Salesforce and UiPath might be question
marks. Axon is already proving its
pricing power. These data centers, they
don't have pricing power. they uh are
receiving a rental return on their
assets that they're paying a premium
for. It's kind of like somebody going
into Southern California and paying a
premium for a bunch of houses, paying
20% above market value. And renting them
out and then going, "Look at all our
cash flow. We just bought all these
houses." But then you look at the
equity, it's like you just overpaid for
all of them. That's bad. You know, we
like to do the opposite. We like to pay
20% under uh market value for these
properties after we fix them up. That's
the wedge, right? So, so that's how we
can take a commodity like housing and
actually turn it into uh something where
we're building wealth up front, but then
we can also piggy bank leverage into
that in the future. Say when rates go
down to zero, we got a huge call option
at the company. Basically
um data centers are like the opposite of
a call option. They are um hot today. I
expect within the next uh 10 years
probably 5 years um these these will be
commoditized and uh the GPU rental rates
are going to compress. Hopefully the
companies will have earned their money
back. But a lot of analysts are
underwriting these companies as if those
rental yields are going to last forever
at shortage rates and they won't. So,
you know, even if you get your money
back on all the hard bear, hopefully you
do, and you pay off your debt, hopefully
you do, if you're still making a yield
by then, great, you're finally
profitable, [laughter] you know? So, you
bought the hardware and which includes
paying off the debt, obviously, uh, and
and now you're cranking a profit. Great,
but how long is that going to last? I
don't buy it. I don't believe it. I
don't think it's going to last that
long. And I I hope I'm wrong because I
think it's keeping the economy going. Uh
so, you know, when I look at a company
like Oracle, I just look at the balance
sheet that they have and it makes me
want to cry uh just looking at how much
debt they have. It's been a minute since
I've looked at the Oracle balance sheet.
So, uh since the question was asked, I'm
going to hop in. Now, just so you know,
while I pull this letter up, uh you can
ask questions as well if you'd like. All
you have to do is download the Meet
Kevin app in the um me uh wait download
the Me Kevin app in the Android or Apple
app store and uh then you too can join
the discussion. All righty. So what do
we have here? Oracle. So this is the
Oracle annual report. Uh and again
forgive me it's been a while since I've
gone through this. So we're just going
to sort of do a live look if you will.
We are recording the video. It's not
live. But we're going to find the
balance sheet here, wherever it is. Oh,
it's coming up. And here we go. So, I've
got cash. Oh, they've raised some money.
It looks like I've got cash of $ 31
billion. That's nice. So, $ 31 billion.
I have bills to pay of 11 + 2.2. 11 +
2.2 plus deferreds I won't include.
11.4. That's 24.6.
notes payable. Uh, plus 7.2. I got 31.8
of bills to pay. Wow. They have
literally just enough cash to pay their
bills. So, I've got just enough cash to
pay their bills. And then this company
literally on top of that has another
$122
billion of debt, not including lease
liabilities, 11.7 of taxes to pay, and
uh I've got other current liabilities of
16.2. So I'm looking at another $150
billion of debt. Now, the issue when
these companies have a lot of debt is
the interest burden at at the interest
rates we're seeing now is a lot. This
company has $150 billion of of uh
long-term debt and it's a $435 billion
market cap company. This is uh they've
got barely enough cash. So, that's a lot
of debt. And if I look at their interest
expense, this makes me nervous, too.
SpaceX is going to end up doing this.
They're going to end up taking on so
much debt. They're going to have this
massive interest expense. So, their
operating income is 20.6 billion.
They're spending almost $5.6 billion on
interest. Obviously, they still have
income though, so that's nice. They
still have earnings. Let's take a look
at their cash flow, though. So, if I
look at their cash flow, net cash
provided by operating activities, 32
billion, but we're spending 55. So,
we're short another 24 over here. So,
where's the money coming from? Oh,
right. We're taking on another 46
billion in debt. Debt scares me because
again, I think these data centers are
going to commoditize and then what do
you end up with? you're ending up with
high interest rate debt on the balance
sheet that's gonna kind of drag you down
like an anchor into the zombie land of a
recession. [laughter]
Okay, now I'm just being hyperbolic, but
that stuff makes me nervous and I think
SpaceX is probably going to head in that
direction, which is a little bit
disappointing, but whatever. Next, uh
this um Omar has a similar question
about these AI infrastructure companies,
NBIS, Iran, and so on and so forth. Uh,
I hate them longterm because I think uh
they'll be bag holders in the future.
Yes, I didn't mention them in the next
hardware uh rally. This is true. I'll
I'll probably do, you know, another dive
on these and I uh and and a lot of these
sort of crypto turn data center plays,
they they're all in the same boat. Uh
they're they're all playing the game of
commodities and it's just not for me.
All right, next question. KPEG versus
PEG. Okay. So, an easy one we could do
here is let's just go to Nvidia.
So, uh what we'll do is we'll make this
very simple so you can see how uh this
um practically plays out. And this is
actually important because there's a
risk factor in PEG ratios that we
frequently forget. Uh so let's take
Nvidia for example and uh what we're
going to do is we're going to look at
their current uh projected I always like
looking at the end of the upcoming year
so that way I get a little bit of a
forward PE ratio. I don't like looking
backwards because if I look backwards
then I have to incorporate growth that
has already occurred and I'm more
interested in forward projecting how
much growth may there be in the future.
Okay, here we go. So, uh current
projected
earnings per share. This is going to be
uh we've got $9 even. All right, so
that's the earnings per share. Now, the
stock price is uh I don't know what's
the puppy trading for 220 or something
like that. Uh okay, there we go. 21755.
Okay. So, to get a PE ratio, we all know
how to do this. All we're going to do is
PE stands for price to earnings. So,
price divided by earnings equals. All
right, there we go. We got a PE ratio of
24. Now, what's the growth rate going to
be for Nvidia? Well, the best way, the
way I like to evaluate growth rates is I
like to take the average of the analyst
or my adjusted forecasts for the next
four years. I'm going to add together uh
these numbers right here. So whatever
these numbers are going to be. So this
is going to be uh forward year 1,
forward
uh year two, right? Forward year three,
forward year four. Okay. Now we're going
to put some growth rates down here. And
these growth rates are going to be the
current forecast from Wall Street. This
is the Wall Street consensus. 43.4
24 91. And then this gets interesting.
-22.6.
Let's pop these. Look at that. So,
you're already seeing that rollover.
Right now, this is actually really
dangerous because first of all, let's
divide this. And this is how you would
normally do the uh PEG ratio. We're
going to divide this by four. Forward
four years. There we go. Now, we have a
growth rate on average over the next
four years of 33.9.
And so now technically if I want to
calculate a PEG ratio, I'm going to go
in here and I'm just going to take
growth divided by just ignore
percentages. The PE ratio, boom. Uh
sorry, I did that the wrong way. Uh it's
going to be the um PE ratio divided by
growth. And there we go. Because growth
is higher than the PE ratio, I know I'm
paying less than a one peg because
that's basically price to earnings.
growth and you literally just did the
math with me. Uh I will just I think
sometimes it's really useful to
visualize how PEG actually uh looks.
Uh when you see this once it it help it
should help you it helped me. Okay, look
you know how to do
the price the PE ratio right? price
uh to earnings.
All right. So if earnings are uh five
and then the price is 100 then in this
case that would be 20. All right. Price
to earnings P E. Okay. Now if I do this
and I put growth right here, I'm
literally just dividing
a ratio that I've already done some
division in. So it's sort of like divide
once, divide again. And then if you look
really closely here, you could actually
see price to earnings growth. [laughter]
See peg. Okay. So like if the growth
year is 20, then the price to earnings
growth is one. 20 divided by 20, right?
All right. Cool.
So um
here's the problem.
And
I struggle with this, but when I look at
a company and I really like it, uh, I
might say, hey, you know, I actually
think the growth rate of this company is
going to be 50. Well, in that case, if I
think the growth rate is going to be 50
and I think analysts are underestimating
the stock, I call it the KPEG, then what
I'm actually going to do is I'm going to
take this divided by 50 and my PEG ratio
looks even cheaper.
That's just an example of a KPEG. But
here's the problem with Nvidia.
I want you to chart this and then you'll
see it much more clearly. And by you
chart this, just watch me chart it. Uh,
that should work. There you go.
Look at this chart. Uh, let's zoom in on
it a little more. Yeah. If we just look
right here. All right. We're kind of
bouncing around between,
you know, 50-ish percent growth. Wow,
sounds good. Maybe a little bit below
that. Okay, call it 40% growth. Sounds
good. But in the last year, it's
actually trending down. Wait, it's
actually trending negative. So what
happens if I get to 2030
and my next growth forecasts for Nvidia
are actually -22.6
-3 -5 -2. In other words, I never get
back to that peak. Well, in this case,
my PEG ratio is actually undefined
because there is no growth. It's just
pure negative. Right? Now, let's say
it's going to be -10
+ 11 and then flat. Okay, so you're
going to have very very little uh I
deleted the formula. Hold on. There we
go. We're going to have very very little
growth here. Let's go with uh -10 11 0
0. There we go. Super low growth.
Uh 0.25. If I now divide this, the PEG
ratio is going to be off the chart.
Ready for this?
uh PE divided by growth peg 96 peg
ratio. You wouldn't touch that with a 20
foot pole, [laughter]
right? So those growth estimates matter
a lot. And this is one of the reasons
why memory stocks look so cheap because
markets know it's going to fall off a
cliff. Well, when I had the other cliff
chart. [laughter]
So,
still got a little bit of that cruise
cold. Hate that. All right, that's K Peg
and Peg. All right, next question. Hey,
Kevin. I have a condo in the greater
Seattle area that I bought for I bought
in 2021 for $55,000.
I don't live there currently. I've
rented it out for $26.50. My monthly
payment is 2550. Okay. So, I mean,
you're going to be upside down
uh because you've got you're probably if
you're I hope you're hiring a manager so
you don't have to deal with the crap,
but you know, then you're going to be a
negative cash flow. You'll be able to
write some of it off. Let's see what's
going on in Seattle. Red Fin data
center. So, the first thing we'll do is
we will look at uh home prices
in uh the Seattle market.
If we can actually get this puppy to
load. There we go.
All right, let's go to metro. Let's see
if we can get Seattle in here. We can.
And let's see how we're doing on the
monthly. Yeah, so year-over-year in
Seattle, median sales price
year-over-year change. Uh, this is kind
of flat. That's going through um that
only goes out to Feb 25. Well, that's
comparing to now. Okay, let me see here.
What do we have here? I mean, it gives
you a summary over here. Here it says
negative about 5%. That's roughly
consistent with what you're talking
about. It doesn't look like we're
falling off a cliff over here. There's
obviously
volatility. This volatility is heavily
interest rate based, right? But it's
actually holding pretty stable. So, the
fact that you're saying, "Hey, uh, you
know, I've seen prices come down over
time from peak of 650 down to 550. Uh I
I don't know if it's been that extreme.
Maybe it has been. Uh but
the overall Seattle area while if you
compare depending on when you bought to
some of these peaks, yeah, prices have
come down. So if I go like peak peak,
peak peak was 870 and now we're 8.27
870 that's about 5%. Right? So 650 times
0.95 brings it down about 617. So, I
don't know that values have come down a
whole hundred grand unless there's
something like special about your condo
neighborhood that's really gone oopsy
dupsies.
But, uh, you've got a loan of $410,000
on it. You put 5% down. The loan is
30-year fixed to 3%. This is an asset.
This is this is an inflationprotected
loan almost. I mean, inflation is higher
than this. This loan gets cheaper every
single month due to inflation alone.
That loan is a steal. I wouldn't want to
get rid of that. And what I would do to
make yourself feel better is I would
look at the principal payown on this.
You owe $410,000. I put down 5% of
purchase. So, you know, let's say you
put down, let's say it was a $450,000
property and you put down 5%. It puts
you at $427 plus pay down a bit. Okay,
fine. So, you've probably got a loan
that's amvertised around 427 on a
30-year fixed. All right, let's type
this up. Amortization table.
uh mortgage.
All right. So, let's grab an
amortization table. Let's see what your
principal payown is. You probably
started at about 427.
Your rate is 3%. You've had it now for 5
years because you bought it in 21,
right? You bought it in 2021. Yeah. So,
you're on five years already. This is
great. Okay. Watch this. Uh where's the
table? Oh, man. They used to give us the
table. Uh, oh, look. End of year five.
How great. What did I say? I hope I said
it out loud. $500.
You're you're probably paying down 500
to 550 bucks a month in principal. So,
even though it feels like you're losing
money, you're you're you've got this
little force savings account and now
you're already itemizing your taxes. If
you're already itemizing your taxes
anyway for a side hustle or other
purposes, you know, any extra expenses
here, property manager, it's just a
write-off. But I would hold this like a
little piggy bank uh and have a manager
deal with it because if you go to sell
it, as desirable as it is to just get
rid of it, here's what it's going to
cost you. It goes out for $550,000.
You're probably going to pay about 7%. 2
and a half to one realtor, two and a
half to another realtor, 1% for closing
costs, 1 and a.5% for bull crap fixes,
maybe even more for repairs. And I'm
just being realistic. You'd probably be
down like to 92% of that value. He just
spent $44,000
just to get rid of the puppy. Why? Keep
that equity, man. [laughter]
Keep the equity. Uh, what do we got
here? My financial position is decent. I
think I got 750 in cash and stocks and
another property in Austin
with a 6 and a half% loan on it. I'd
start paying off that $270,000 loan.
That's what I would do. You got cash and
stocks. Good for I mean, you're doing
good. you know, you're gonna like you're
not dying for the 90 grand you're going
to get out of that condo. Instead,
take some of that cash and pay down your
Austin property at six and a half. Come
on, that's an easy rate of return right
there. Get rid of that. [laughter]
6 and a2%. I like that already. Anyway,
all right, let's do another one. How
would you [clears throat] invest as an
18-year-old who works for his dad who
farms? So, your dad farms or you farm
and doesn't get paid the traditional
way, meaning getting paid with a pickup
and things like that. Okay. I want to
get into farming, but finding land that
a beginner can afford is hard. I'm not
going to college because I don't see the
point. I have a Weeble account
and I'm up a little bit, but I struggle
finding a stock before it goes up. What
would you do to make more money and
invest?
Well, well, son, look, it all comes down
to income potential. You know, farming
is very hard work, but it can also be
very rewarding.
And so, I would be very real with your
dad and ask, "Hey,
you know, is this a business we can grow
together?
Father, son, can we crank this business
and make some more money?" I don't know,
maybe he's already making good money,
right? But I would be having those
questions
and
you know the fact that you're not
getting paid in the traditional way
suggests maybe the answer is no. Uh and
then I would try to figure out what what
is it going to take for us to actually
legitimize this. Can we get this set up
as an S corporation or an LLC? Can we
get on W2s?
Let's get some retirement stuff going.
401ks, Roth, whatever.
Let's get company health insurance. It's
tax write off that way anyway. you got
to pay health insurance anyway and let's
turn this into a real business. What's
it going to take for us to expand and
grow? Whether it's uh more livestock or
or land I I I don't know, right? Those
are all the question. But those are the
things I would ask. in that I would kind
of sus out what is the potential here
because I mean I I don't want to dump on
you know anybody's business but like if
if your parents are point blank or your
father's point blank to you go look you
know this this gets us by it pays the
bills but
you know we're we're running against the
clock like I don't know maybe maybe
there's some idiosyncratic reasons that
there's an issue to the longevity or the
longevity potential right of the actual
business, then uh I would want to know
that. And then maybe, like I said
earlier at the very beginning of this
video, I'd uh you know, at the same
time, I'd be starting maybe a side
hustle and something else. You don't
have to go to college uh if that's not
what you want to do. There there are
plenty of uh businesses you can do out
there. So, something to think about. All
right,
let's do another one. So, lack of
swagger says, "Hey, Kev, love your
content. With the IPOs of Anderil and
OpenAI being a possibility in the near
future, what are your thoughts on
investing New Burst Pro? Should you
consider them? Look, I think Ander is
going to be a bitching company, like
really exciting. Very, very cool. Um,
but and you know, less excited about
OpenAI, but we'll see. And I'm not
trying to blow it off, but it's for me
it's really hard to say, "Hey, how
should you feel about the IPO?" Until I
see the financials. The financials tell
me everything. And everybody watching
should get good at reading financial
statements. You should know what the
three basic financial statements are.
Very simple. Income statement, balance
sheet, cash flow statement. Very
important.
And and how they affect each other. The
three components of the balance sheet,
the operating or of the cash flow
statement, the operating cash flows, the
investing cash flow, the financing
section, what goes where. Capex is an
investment.
You know, salaries for your GNA
expenses. Well, those are operating
expenses. They're not actually on the
cash flow statement. They're on your
income statement, but they flow through
the cash flow statement. How? They show
up as a net income at the top, right?
That's important. And so, what I would
do to prep for any kind of IPO, study
financial statements. So that way when
your favorite company's coming up for
IPO, you could scrub that puppy and you
could defend it. Because that way if you
buy it and it goes down in value, you
know, you're not going to get your boot
shaken out of that stock. You could
defend your ownership of that stock. I
think that's valuable. All right.
Somebody else says, "Hey, Kevin, are you
still bullish Meta by the end of the
year?"
Meta for me, I think, has some really
good long-term opportunities. I see them
as an advertising play more so than just
a midterm elections play or or even a
presidential election play. I see them
as
probably the greatest beneficiary of
artificial intelligence enhanced
advertising ever. Advertising is going
to get so good. And with three billion
daily active users, daily active users,
Zuck has got people by the
impressive. So for me, I look less at
the data center leases. Uh I do know
they have outs on some of these and I
think Zuck is kind of getting a little
smart with the program here of like
let's get more people into the meadow
meta ecosystem so we can advertise to
them, give away the LLM stuff. It's kind
of smart, but he's pivoting, right? He's
like, "Wait, we don't want to be a
Frontier Lab." And he's pivoting exactly
the way he should in my opinion. So I'm
optimistic on it. You know, I've got a
price target of like 1377 for the
company. None of this in the video is
personalized financial advice.
Uh, what do you know now about finding
the beauty in life that you wish you
knew earlier? Um, wow. Well, as a ripe
34y old, let me tell you [laughter]
no. Uh I I think um
probably the biggest thing is that
everybody in life ends up having these
regrets and and they just nag at you.
Like when people hear the word regret,
they often get like a little eye watery
and like emotional because it's like,
"Oh man, the time I effed up and I did
this or I shouldn't have done this or I
shouldn't have taken that contract. I
shouldn't have worked with that person.
I shouldn't have done that." Whatever.
Or worse, the inverse. I wish I did do
this. I wish I did XYZ. Right? the would
a could a shoulda eat you alive and
anything you can do to just look and go
man
got good things right now maybe it's not
everything we want but is it a good life
hopefully the answer to that is yes you
know I I don't know what your situation
is but uh
we tend to mentally as humans uh have a
really hard time living in the present
people always say oh live in the present
live every moment like it's last you
can't you're hardwired to think about
what can I do differently in the future
to preserve myself, my income, my
family's income, whatever, right? That's
hard. And uh it it's something that um
the sooner you can come to grips with
just sort of getting over regrets, the
more unstoppable you become. And I think
honestly the best example of that of
somebody who just doesn't give a flying
f probably to a fault is Donald Trump.
[laughter]
Dude, the guy's got plenty to regret uh
in so many angles and uh he just doesn't
seem to care. Maybe it's because he's
richer now than he ever was before and
it sort of papered over it all.
[laughter]
But uh man,
um even I remember, you know, back in
2021,
2022,
the guy kind of disappeared for a while,
more in 21. And when he came out and he
did his campaign speeches, he seemed
kind of miserable.
Guy campaigned for like what felt like
two and a half years
to get back into the office and somehow
he swallowed all his guilt,
frustrations, whatever, and and crank to
get back. Uh so you got to give him
credit for that. Uh, a lot of people,
you know, have not so nice things to say
about Donald Trump. This is not a
political video, but I think as as an
example or testament to an example that
that I think is quite interesting.
Uh,
all right. Last question we have here is
the following. Hey Kevin, I wasn't able
to get into the first investment of
Reinvest because I didn't have the
liquidity in time. I was wondering if
the minimum is still going to be 10K in
the next goound. Uh, just so I can look
to set aside some dollars. All right.
So, we're not 100% sure yet on the
minimum. Once we set the minimum, you
know, if you're in the position where
you were going to invest previously and
you missed it previously and you want to
invest in this round, maybe you have a
little bit less uh than the minimum. I
can't promise it, but you can always
email us at ir@houseack.com.
You can mention this video. Uh but um so
I don't know uh exactly what the final
situation is going to be. We haven't
filed yet, but we are planning on filing
a fund raise. Uh and so we'll see. It
should be a preferred dividend yielder,
which I think will be really cool. And
uh I'm very excited because it is going
to refill the pot to for us to go buy
some wedge deals and keep developing uh
the real estate that we are. We've got
plenty of cash to develop a lot of our
real estate, but we want to develop even
more and uh buy some more wedge deals
and then of course keep expanding what
we're doing with artificial
intelligence. Uh so we're really
excited. Uh we we'll see though, you
know, we'll wait for a filing to come
and then we'll have a whole lot more
details and disclosures and risks,
right? Obviously, this isn't a
solicitation. There is no offering. So,
uh yeah, we'll see. But, uh thank you.
Thanks. Thanks for mentioning the
interest. And uh folks, if you want to
leave a comment, yeah, feel free to do
so as well. Download the Meek Kevin app
in the Apple or Android app store. Once
you sign up uh with your email, or you
could sign in [music] with Gmail,
whatever is easier for you. Um that's
what I do. I just sign in with Gmail cuz
I don't have to save another password
that way. Uh once you set up an account
on the actual app on your phone, you
could also go to app.meke.com
and use the app there. Thank you so much
for [music] watching and we'll see you
in the next video. Goodbye everybody and
good luck.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, [music] man. You have
done so much. People love you. People
look up to you.
>> Kevin Pra there, financial analyst and
YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your [music] take.